It won't be the first time Jerry will be here. Well thank you everyone. Thank
you Jerry for the beautiful
introduction and we truly have been friends for a long long time. I'd like to
congratulate my fellow inductees, the accomplishments, the hard work, the
service to your communities as just for Mark was and it is an honor for me to
be inducted with you. Congratulations to all of you.
I'd like to thank Debbie and Ann Hanson, number one, for steadfastly working on
linking the
diverse ethnic communities of Cleveland and making the connections to bring us
together and for establishing the International Hall of Fame. We owe them a
tremendous debt. Thank you so much to both of you. To my husband who is sitting
over there, Bob Crawford, come on Bob, stand up.
As most of you know, I'm going to be anywhere with Bob. We both work together
on all of our activities and without his support it wouldn't happen.
To my family and friends who came today to celebrate this great event and who
always support me in my efforts, no matter whether you think I'm crazy or not,
they're always there taking the ideas, moving forward and always listening to
me say, "Don't worry, it'll be easier next year."
Right? To the members of the Cleveland Cultural Gardens and to the members of
the Ancient World of Hibernians, thank you so much for your continued support
and your
friendship and faith that means so much to me. The Murphy Irish Art Center is
the Irish dance school I started 40 years ago and I decided on the name Arts
because we wanted to promote more than just traditional Irish dancing.
A lot of what service I've done has come from my parents, as Jerry suggested,
and my grandfather danced when he came here from Ireland and from that point my
mother
wanted one of her children to take Irish dance and I was the one lucky enough
to get the lessons. I have now been teaching Irish dance for 40 years and have
had thousands of students come through our center.
It's provided much more than just teaching Irish dance, but it's been an
opportunity to promote Irish culture to them. It's been an ability to develop
and grow and make them use their talents to inspire them to do the work.
To do better than they ever thought they could. To even get to the World
Championships and the Murphy Irish Art Center and our dancers brought a World
Championship to Cleveland before the Cavs did.
[applause]
I'm here to teach Irish dance, primarily at nursing homes and senior citizen
buildings all across County and I teach the children to give back their talents
to respect their older citizens, to learn how important they are.
After we finish dancing, students are encouraged to go out and individually
shake their hands and let them touch their costumes and let them say hello. It's
such an important part of what we do. It's much, much more than just teaching
dance.
In addition, we get the opportunity to inspire them to achieve enough that they
can actually get to the World Championships. We have to qualify, we have to go
through an awful lot of effort. Then we get to take hundreds of people to
Ireland with us as we've done over 40 years and show them our beautiful country.
Many of our students decide then to go to school abroad because they're
comfortable with travel and foreign life, but most of all they learn to love
Ireland and they frequently go back, which is the goal.
So we've had a wonderful run for 40 years and hopefully will go on for a lot
longer, but it isn't a one person act without all the teachers that I have and
the wonderful support of our parents who really volunteer so many hours to make
all of our activities happen.
We wouldn't be successful at all, so thank you to all of you.
And going back to Jerry's story, you know, meeting him in the Irish Garden in
1961, I used to go to all the cultural garden meetings and I tell people about
this and I think they believe me but I'm not quite sure.
But I've been going to meetings for over 50 years. As I was a child working in
that garden, I used to go to the meetings with my mother because she was the
Irish delegate and we would have meetings in the red room at City Hall.
And I've been with almost every president of the cultural gardens except for
the first two. And so going back to St. Grinsky, sitting in the red room in the
mayor's office with a big cigar out of his mouth and running his meetings
etched a memory I'll never forget.
And going on through the future to Richard Conish
and the cultural gardens that I think is just fantastic. So I appreciate all of
them coming. We've seen a tremendous growth. We celebrated our 100th
anniversary in 2016. And the cultural gardens are so unique.
We are symbolic. We are historic. We are an artistic treasure of the city of
Cleveland.
Today Mayor Jackson and our city councilmen who are here tonight and our Cuyahoga
County officials for continuing to make Cleveland a place that honors diversity
and encourages ethnic pride.
That is so important to all of us. Cleveland is a different place because of
the ethnic groups that are the fabric of our city.
And when you look at our festivals and our churches, our music, our plays, our
dance, our civic and cultural organizations and of course the cultural gardens,
you can see all of that flourishing in a wonderful harmony.
So a whole group of people of Cleveland will come from different ethnic
backgrounds, have really made Cleveland what it is today. And all of you who
are here today are tremendous examples of that where you volunteer and you
inspire the younger generations to do the same.
That's how I learned to volunteer and I'm hoping that that's how the younger
generations are going to continue all the hard work that we've done.
So I thank you all for doing that. It's so important to model, not just to tell
someone to do something, but to actually judge yourself and work with them side
by side.
It will make so much more of an impact than simply getting directions. So I
want to ask you to support the cultural gardens. All of us here today belong to
it.
There's a garden you can join and represent and work for. I encourage you to
come to One World Day. It's September 16th on Sunday and be part of a glorious
celebration of all that makes all of our homelands absolutely beautiful.
So thank you very much. All of you with this community of diverse backgrounds
has brought richness and success and true joy to our city of Cleveland. Thank
you very much.